Guide to the Barbara Hammer Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Teaching notes, 1970-2010; Series III; 7.58; (7 boxes)
  - Graduate course packet for "The Body as a Site of Representation", 1994 (Box 45)
- Audiovisual materials, circa 1974-2017; Series IV; 8.75; (21 boxes)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Contains materials related to Barbara Hammer's work as a filmmaker and artist including raw and edited footage of films from across her career, along with documentation of events. Item description transcribed from existing labels on media items.
  - Capetown Tape #2: Workshop, Sheila, baboons 12/13, undated; 1 (Box 46)
  - Sound Guguletu: Zoleka, kiddo, FAB, undated; 1 (Box 46)
  - Pix Guguletu: Zoleka, kiddo, FAB, undated; 1 (Box 46)
  - Robbin Island Prison, KRUGER ANIMALS, undated; 1 (Box 46)
  - Soweto class and shebeen, 1994-07-03; 1 (Box 46)
  - Opening night Cape Town, party stories, undated; 1 (Box 46)
  - Nomkhita and Zoleka editing, 1995-11-; 1 (Box 46)
  - Kevin Botha, Streets of J'burg, Panel, 1995-07-04-1995-07-05; 1 (Box 46)
  - S.A. narration, undated; 1 (Box 46)
  - Chicken dinner at Zoleka's sister's in Guguletu, 1999-09-11; 1 (Box 46)
  - Justin's Tape: additional footage of people in Cape Town for Barbara, undated; 1 (Box 46)
  - Out in South Africa opening, 1994-11-09; 1 (Box 46)
  - Workshop Soweto, 1994-07-03; 1 (Box 46)
  - South African Lesbian Forum and interviews--Tape 3, undated; 1 (Box 46)
  - Kwathema Township Tape 6, 1994-07; 1 (Box 46)
  - Pick-ups S.A., undated; 1 (Box 46)
  - Tape 1 South Africa, 1994-06-27-1994-06-28; 1 (Box 46)
  - Aftermath, 2001-09-2001-10; 3 (Box 46)
  - Ground Zero, 2002-09-10; 1 (Box 46)
  - Our Grief is not A Cry For War, 2002-2003; 4 (Box 46)
  - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 47)
  - Tape 68 Okazaki, undated; 1 (Box 47)
  - Tape 69 Kikuchi, 1999-11-22; 1 (Box 47)
  - Tape 72 Sato and Shuichu, 1999-11; 1 (Box 47)
  - Louisa Burnham Les Milles Tape 3, 1999-05-28; 1 (Box 47)
  - 29 - Hiroko 2, undated; 1 (Box 47)
  - 30 - Hiroko 3 / Nogami / Haneda 1, undated; 1 (Box 47)
  - 31 - Haneda 2 / Fuseya 1, undated; 1 (Box 47)
  - 32 - Fuseya 2, undated; 1 (Box 47)
  - 34 - Fuseya and Yumiko, undated; 1 (Box 47)
  - 4 - iizuka 2, undated; 1 (Box 47)
  - 5 - iizuka 3, undated; 1 (Box 47)
  - 6 - iizuka 4 / Yumiko 1, undated; 1 (Box 47)
  - 8 - Diary 1, undated; 1 (Box 47)
  - 16 - H and W 3 / Farmwoman 1, undated; 1 (Box 47)
  - 17 - Student Party / Kato 1, undated; 1 (Box 47)
  - 18 - Kato 2, undated; 1 (Box 47)
  - Devotion transcripts: Japanese and English, undated; 1 (Box 47)
  - 44 - EXP. MT / Sato 1, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - 74 - First blow Magino, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - #51, 1998-11-22; 1 (Box 48)
  - 14 - Kawanaka 2 Hara and Watanabe 1, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - Final Final cut "Devotion", undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - 52 - Study film S-R-7-2 / 8 / S-R-5-1, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - 53 - Study film S-R-5-2 / 8, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - 55 - Museya 2, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - RC #2 My output Devotion - first part, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - Devotion My output Rough cut 2 - pt. 2, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - Oshima visits OP '81, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - 61 - Translation BETA 1 & 2, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - 7 - Yumiko 2, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - 63 - Translation BETA 3, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - Sea of youth Sound bites, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - 33 - Fuseya 3, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - 35 - Shiraishi House Tour 1, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - 36 - S. House tour 2 / Sea of Youth / Partisans, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - 37 - S. Interview #2 Pt. 1 / Bullet & Study film, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - 38 - Stufy film 8 / S. Interview #2 Pt. 2, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - 54 - Museya 1, 1998-10-20; 1 (Box 48)
  - 59 - BETA 4: Study film - Reels 5 & 6, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - Tape 65 Kramer, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - Tape 67 Hara Kazuo, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - OSHIMA 64 Rice fields MASUYA Suichi, 1999-11-30; 1 (Box 48)
  - 56 - BETA 1: Snow / Last Day, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - 57 - BETA 2: Memorial, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - 58 - BETA 3: Compilation, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - 68 - Gentan, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - 73 - Footage, undated; 1 (Box 48)
  - 19 - Father & Brother 1, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 20 - Father & Bro. 2 / Mikado 1, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 21 - Mikado 2, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 22 - Mikado 3 / Izumu 1, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 23 - Izumu 2, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 25 - Tsuchimoto 2 / Sento 1, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 26 - Sento 2 / Niwa 1, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 27 - Niwa 2 / Shimizu 1, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 28 - Shimizu 2 / Hiroko 1, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - Tape 71 Iizuka / Abe, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - Sea of Youth Sound Bites, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 47 - EXP. Magino House 2, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 48 - EXP. Magino House 3, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 49 - Magino VIII 1 (Farmer/Cooking/Tractor), undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 50 - Study film 2 / Magino VIII. 2 (Rice harvest/Bathroom), undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 63 - Cemetery sunset / Steenbeck same as Tape 60, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 75 - DEVOTION Title seq., undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 76 Tape 1 KOGO Ogawa pro, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - Devotion new credit sequence, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 1 - Izuru / EXP. SKY, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 2 - Izuru 2 / Idemitsu 1, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 3 - Idemitsu 2 / Iizuka 1, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 15 - H & W 2, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 24 - izumu 3 / Tsuchimoto 1, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 60 - BETA 5: Study film - Silent Reel 7, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - FINAL SEQUENCE WEXNER 1, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - CHAR ASS CREDITS, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - DEVOTION / Timecode, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - B. HAMMER JOST, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - Tape 66 JON JOST, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 46 - EXP. Magino House 1, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 45 - Sato 2, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - Dat 2 Copy, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - OGAWA TALKS, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 9- Diary 2 / Hatano 1, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 10 - Hatano 2, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 11 - Hatano 3 / Noriko 1, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 12 - Noriko 2 / Heta Village, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 13 - Heta Vill 2 / Hatano grave / Kawanaka, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 39 - Interview #2, Pt. 3, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 40 - S. Waterfall, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 41 - Daisuke 1 @ Restaurant, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 42 - Daisuke 2 @ Image Forum 43 - Daisuke 3 @ Image Forum, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - Tape 70 Kikuchi / Kuroki / Iizuka, undated; 1 (Box 49)
  - 1. Ukraine, 1997-06-30; 1 (Box 50)
  - 2. Ukraine, 1997-07-01; 1 (Box 50)
  - 3. Ukraine, undated; 1 (Box 50)
  - 4. Ukraine, Kiev, 1997-07-02; 1 (Box 50)
  - 5. Ukraine / Kiev / LOST TIME CODE, undated; 1 (Box 50)
  - 6. Ukraine Kiev, 1997-07-03; 1 (Box 50)
  - 7. Ukraine Kiev Greesha, 1997-07-04; 1 (Box 50)
  - 8. Ukraine / Kiev, 1997-07-04; 1 (Box 50)
  - 9. Ukraine / Kiev Paola, 1997-07-05; 1 (Box 50)
  - 10. Ukraine / Kiev, 1997-07-04-1997-07-05; 1 (Box 50)
  - 11. Poor Market, 1997-07-05; 1 (Box 50)
  - 12. Ukraine / Kiev Oxanna + Ludmilla, 1997-07-06; 1 (Box 50)
  - 13. Ludmilla dinner Greesha photos, 1997-07-06; 1 (Box 50)
  - 14. Ukraine Kiev Ivanna Kampala, 1997-07-06; 1 (Box 50)
  - 15. Ukraine Kieve Ivanna Kampala Train ride, 1997-07-07; 1 (Box 50)
  - 16 Ukraine Ternopil detective work, undated; 1 (Box 50)
  - 17. UK. Strevka, 1997-07-08; 1 (Box 50)
  - 18. Ukraine Strevka, 1997-07-08; 1 (Box 50)
  - 19. Ukraine Ternopil Ivan Prankist, 1997-07-09; 1 (Box 50)
  - 20. Ukraine / I. frankisko / Kolonyacha, 1997-07-10; 1 (Box 50)
  - 21. Ukraine Kolycleum / Kosiv, 1997-07-12; 1 (Box 50)
  - 22. Ukraine / Lviv / graves + singing, 1997-07-13; 1 (Box 50)
  - 23. Ukraine / Lviv / Odessa, 1997-07-16-1997-07-17; 1 (Box 50)
  - 24. Ukraine / Odesa, 1997-07-16; 1 (Box 50)
  - 25. Ukraine / Odessa, undated; 1 (Box 50)
  - 26. Odessa Ukraine, undated; 1 (Box 50)
  - 27. Ukraine / Kiev Babi Yar, 1997-07-22; 1 (Box 50)
  - 26. Ukraine Odessa Kiev 2, undated; 1 (Box 50)
  - 29. Ukraine / Kiev 2 Parajanov, 1997-07-22; 1 (Box 50)
  - 29 Ukraine Kiev artists gay, 1997-07-23; 1 (Box 50)
  - 30. Ukraine Kiev check, undated; 1 (Box 50)
  - 31. Ukraine / Kiev 2, undated; 1 (Box 50)
  - 34. New Lesbians, undated; 1 (Box 50)
  - My Babushka Dubs, undated; 1 (Box 50)
  - My Babushka, undated; 2 (Box 50)
  - My Babushka / Final Cut, 11/3/00; 1 (Box 50)
  - My Babushka (Back-up), undated; 1 (Box 50)
  - My Babushka second time tape used, undated; 1 (Box 50)
  - Tape 1 Lilia Taraneko Founder Ganimed, Kiev, Ukraine, 1998-04-10; 1 (Box 50)
  - Tape 2 Lilia + Viktoria Taranenko + cutaways Kiev, 1998-04-10; 1 (Box 50)
  - Breast Cancer HIV / Deaf Linda Cummings, 1993-12-19; 1 (Box 51)
  - Shirley Sellars #2 lee Baxter, 1993-12-19; 1 (Box 51)
  - Phyllis Ip Run for the Cure, 1993-10-23; 1 (Box 51)
  - Amanda Cordero Breast cancer interview, 1993-12-03; 1 (Box 51)
  - Run for the Cure Ezter Freeman, 1993-10-25; 1 (Box 51)
  - Shirley Sellars, 1993-12-04; 1 (Box 51)
  - F. BSE + mammo Cathe Merschel, 1993-10-17; 1 (Box 51)
  - Joyce Chin, 1993-10-26; 1 (Box 51)
  - Cancer interviews Birkby, 1990; 1 (Box 51)
  - Eva Swan - Breast cancer, 1991-12-08; 1 (Box 51)
  - Sonogram: Breasts, 1997-02-20; 1 (Box 52)
  - Check-up + Penny 18, undated; 1 (Box 52)
  - Barbara Hammer X-RAY TRT, undated; 1 (Box 52)
  - OLD SKIN, undated; 1 (Box 52)
  - SEQ 2, undated; 1 (Box 52)
  - Seq 1 Jitter, undated; 1 (Box 52)
  - Jitter 2, 2005-04-08; 1 (Box 52)
  - Old skin Alfred Univ 16, undated; 1 (Box 52)
  - Casper, Chesapeake Josephine, undated; 1 (Box 52)
  - BH - Memorial Sloan Kettering, 2006-07-21; 1 (Box 52)
  - Tape 1 Contessa, undated; 1 (Box 52)
  - White horse, racehorse rodeo, 2007-09-24; 1 (Box 52)
  - Western Encounters, undated; 1 (Box 52)
  - Western Encounters 2, undated; 1 (Box 52)
  - Cambodia Aspen New Mexico Ghost Ranch, undated; 1 (Box 52)
  - #9 HF Bar Ranch, undated; 1 (Box 52)
  - Ghost Ranch, undated; 1 (Box 52)
  - Red Reflet Ranch #1, 2007-10; 1 (Box 52)
  - Red Reflet ranch #2, undated; 1 (Box 52)
  - Red Reflet 3, undated; 1 (Box 52)
  - Notes on Old Skin, 2005-06-21; 1 (Box 52)
  - Korea - found tapes, undated; 2 (Box 53)
  - Tapes labeled in Korean, 2000-10-30-2000-11-02; 5 (Box 53)
  - Group of photographs, undated; ca. 40 (Box 53)
  - Chenju-do 1, undated; 1 (Box 54)
  - JEJU 2, undated; 1 (Box 54)
  - Jeju 3, undated; 1 (Box 54)
  - Cheju 5, undated; 1 (Box 54)
  - Chejudo 7, undated; 1 (Box 54)
  - Chenju do 8mm transfer, undated; 1 (Box 54)
  - Barbara Hammer, undated; 1 (Box 54)
  - Audiocassette in Korean, undated; 1 (Box 54)
  - Barbara Ward E E Cummings, undated; 1 (Box 55)
  - Betsy Belote, therapy session / BHammer, ca. 1975; 1 (Box 55)
  - Kitchen Talk 1 Jane Brakhage, 1974-01-09; 1 (Box 55)
  - Green House 1 Jane Brakhage, 1974-01-09; 1 (Box 55)
  - Reel-01-A_BH_Masturbation Fantasies, circa 1975-1976; 1 (Box 55)
  - Edited Lesbos Feminist Institute Tape, undated; 1 (Box 55)
  - Joyce Culver's Photo Shoot Barbara + Florrie, 1991; 1 (Box 55)
  - Erotica: 1899-1929, 2015-03-16; 1 (Box 55)
  - Still Point film dub, 1989; 1 (Box 55)
  - Barbara + Florrie, 2013-12-08; 1 (Box 55)
  - Kitchen talk II Jane Brakhage, 1974-01-09; 1 (Box 56)
  - Jane plays recorder Stan +recorder, undated; 1 (Box 56)
  - Hooking #1, undated; 1 (Box 56)
  - Hooking #2 Artists and economics Maya Deren, undated; 1 (Box 56)
  - Green house 2 Jane Brakhage, 1974-01-09; 1 (Box 56)
  - Grandma, 1974-04-29; 1 (Box 56)
  - Reel-07-A Kate Millett, Audre Lorde, UCLA First Lesbian Conference - part of "X" soundtrack, 1973-1975; 1 (Box 56)
  - Reel-06-A Sexuality Workshop First Lesbian Conference UCLA, 1975; 1 (Box 56)
  - Reel-04-A Soundtrack for Be Mine Valentine, circa 1985; 1 (Box 56)
  - Reel-05-A John W. Hammer tells stories about "Barbie", Barbara Hammer, his daughter, 1978-10-31; 1 (Box 56)
  - Resisting Paradise - postcards, 1999; 1 (Box 57)
  - Resisting Paradise - Reel 1 Mono Mix, 2003-01-15; 1 (Box 57)
  - Resisting Paradise - Reel 2 Mono Mix, 2003-01-15; 1 (Box 57)
  - Resisting Paradise - Reel 3 Mono Mix, 2003-01-15; 1 (Box 57)
  - Resisting Paradise - Reel 1 Mono MIx, 2003-02-07; 1 (Box 57)
  - Matisse soundtrack, undated; 1 (Box 57)
  - French Hammer, undated; 1 (Box 57)
  - DAT RP, undated; 1 (Box 57)
  - Les Plus Belles Marches Militaires, undated; 1 (Box 57)
  - Chants du Pays Profond, undated; 1 (Box 57)
  - Matisse Voice, undated; 1 (Box 57)
  - Requesting Paradise - Tape (UB) 1 Reel 1, 2001-09-10; 1 (Box 57)
  - Requesting Paradise - Tape (UB) 2 - Reel 2, 2002-09-10; 1 (Box 57)
  - Requesting Paradise - Tape (UB) 3 - Reel 3, 2001-09-10; 1 (Box 57)
  - Requesting Paradise - Tape (UB) 4 - Reel 4, 2001-09-10; 1 (Box 57)
  - Requesting Paradise - Tape (UB) 1 - CR# 1-6, 2002-01-30; 1 (Box 57)
  - Requesting Paradise - Tape (UB) 2 - CR# 7-13, 2002-01-30; 1 (Box 57)
  - Requesting Paradise - Tape (UB) 3 - CR# COLOR LABE NEG, 2002-01-30; 1 (Box 57)
  - Requesting Paradise - CR# UN1-UN3, 2002-09-12; 1 (Box 57)
  - Requesting Paradise - CR# UN1-UN3, 2002-09-12; 1 (Box 57)
  - Requesting Paradise - CR 1-3 TCHR 21, 2002-09-26; 1 (Box 57)
  - Requesting Paradise - CR# 1-3, undated; 1 (Box 57)
  - Requesting Paradise Print, 2001-12-13; 1 (Box 57)
  - #1, 2002-11-12; 1 (Box 58)
  - #2, 2002-11-12; 1 (Box 58)
  - 005 - Monique Camargo - Soundtrack - Nuns, undated; 1 (Box 58)
  - 006 - Josette Vincensini et Marie-Ange Allibert + Rodriguez, 1999-03-24-1999-03-25; 1 (Box 57)
  - 007 Rene Dijon, undated; 1 (Box 58)
  - 008 - Germaine Cremieux, 1999-05-10; 1 (Box 58)
  - 009 Lisa Fittko, 2000-07-06; 1 (Box 58)
  - 010 Lisa Fittko Tape 2, undated; 1 (Box 58)
  - 011 Lisa Fittko Tape 3, undated; 1 (Box 58)
  - 012 Joseph Gurland, 2001-10-14; 1 (Box 58)
  - 13 Henry Gurland xerox, undated; 1 (Box 58)
  - 16 Voice overs, undated; 1 (Box 58)
  - 19 VO Alvin Epstein Claude Dethuit, undated; 1 (Box 58)
  - 20 Claude Dethuit Jacqueline Monnier, undated; 1 (Box 58)
  - 020 French Bonnard Matisse, undated; 1 (Box 58)
  - 21 VO Maurice Jospe, undated; 1 (Box 58)
  - 24 RP My questions, undated; 1 (Box 58)
  - 024 My new narration, 2002-05-20; 1 (Box 58)
  - Resisting Paradise Reel 01, undated; 1 (Box 58)
  - Resisting Paradise 02, undated; 1 (Box 58)
  - Resisting Paradise Final Reel 03, undated; 1 (Box 58)
  - Voice Overs Tape 15, undated; 1 (Box 58)
  - RP sample Louise singing, undated; 1 (Box 58)
  - Frances DuMaurier Matisse, 2002-12-10; 1 (Box 58)
  - Jacque as Matisse, undated; 1 (Box 58)
  - RP: Flatbed, music, Matisse painting, undated; 1 (Box 58)
  - "Why New York" Tina Vammer from Copenhagen Interview, 1985-08-01; 1 (Box 59)
  - Barbara Hammer interview (Yishai Elder) Israel Radio, 2003-07-19; 1 (Box 59)
  - Representation of Women lecture Evergreen State College, 1987-01; 1 (Box 59)
  - Eel river, Doll House Storm de Hirsch, 1984-03; 1 (Box 59)
  - WBAI interview of B. Hammer by Prarie Miller - Tobaron Waxman, 2003-05; 1 (Box 59)
  - 28 - This is the side, undated; 1 (Box 59)
  - Does Radical Content Require Radical Form?, 1988; 2 (Box 59)
  - Tunisia, 1985-06-28; 1 (Box 59)
  - Barbara Hammer at Millenium Film Workshop, 1980-02-12; 1 (Box 59)
  - B. Hammer discussion / London Filmmaker's co-op Bristol, 1981-10; 1 (Box 59)
  - Millenium class Sari Arledge, Shirley Clark, Storm de Hirsch, 1984-12-04; 1 (Box 59)
  - La Noche mas corta No. 40 Corto Lesbianas, 2000-05-29; 1 (Box 59)
  - Interview: B. Hammer / clips shown on Spanish television, 2000-08-22; 1 (Box 59)
  - 22 Frameline Award, 2000; 1 (Box 59)
  - Presentation on 5/6/98 by B. Hammer Ohio University / Athens Film Festival, 1998-05-06; 1 (Box 59)
  - Barbara Hammer news reels from 8 in 8, undated; 1 (Box 60)
  - 25 - A Brief History of the Festival Frameline, undated; 1 (Box 60)
  - EIGHT IN EIGHT Tape 1 for English text please touch breast model, undated; 1 (Box 60)
  - "fagtactics" Scott Berry, 2002; 1 (Box 60)
  - Sundance Channel Barbara Hammer Interview, undated; 1 (Box 60)
  - The Mirror of Maya Deren and B.H. in After Effects, undated; 1 (Box 60)
  - 27 "Our tape" Mireille + Barbara, 1986-03; 1 (Box 60)
  - Your Turn - To Mireille from Barbara, undated; 1 (Box 60)
  - A "Yes" Tape, undated; 1 (Box 60)
  - You/Me, undated; 1 (Box 60)
  - The Rules of Attraction conference... Working at the edges panel, undated; 1 (Box 60)
  - Barbara Hammer teaching Super 8 Museum School of Fine Arts, 1997; 1 (Box 60)
  - Batteau Mouche, undated; 1 (Box 60)
  - Archival audio footage, undated; 1 (Box 60)
  - B. Hammer interview, 1993-01-29; 1 (Box 60)
  - Lecture Ohio Uni. School of Film by Barnara Hammer, 2001-04-09; 1 (Box 61)
  - Sundance Channel Snapshot Diaries Compilation, undated; 1 (Box 61)
  - From It's Right Now - Sundance Channel Snapshot Diaries, 2001; 1 (Box 61)
  - "Devotion" trailer, undated; 1 (Box 61)
  - Frameline - A Brief History of the Festival, 2001-06-21-2001-06-24; 1 (Box 61)
  - Peep Show found footage projector play by B.H., undated; 1 (Box 61)
  - EIGHT IN EIGHT Tape 2 Spanish por favor, toca breast model, undated; 1 (Box 61)
  - SAVE SEX, undated; 1 (Box 61)
  - 2 Skelly Proc, Interviews, Words Phyllis Berkby, undated; 1 (Box 62)
  - DYKE TV, undated; 1 (Box 62)
  - Master B. Hammer Panel S.F., undated; 1 (Box 62)
  - 1 Skel Proc, Curie..., undated; 1 (Box 62)
  - Kiev, Ukraine Discussion after My Babushka, 2001-12; 1 (Box 62)
  - In the Mirror of Maya Deren Aftereffect, 2001; 1 (Box 62)
  - Barbara Hammer "Lesbian hands" Berlin, Pelze, 1991-07-04; 1 (Box 63)
  - Animation and Optical printing class films - California College of Arts and Crafts, 1988; 1 (Box 63)
  - New Years Resolutions - Babara and Florrie, 1989-01-01; 1 (Box 63)
  - Whitney Museum American Art Today, 1989 Biennial - "Just My Part", 1 (Box 63)
  - Experimental Film Congress, Toronto, Ontario, 1988-05; 1 (Box 63)
  - Marilyn and Barbara go Clamming / Barbara Mediates on the Northwest, 1988; 1 (Box 63)
  - "Does Radical Content Deserve Radical Form?" -, 1988-09-17; 1 (Box 63)
  - Florrie / Watson (excerpts), undated (Box 63)
  - 8 in 8 Tape II, undated; 1 (Box 64)
  - Lesbian Central, undated; 1 (Box 64)
  - Barbara Hammer Special Screening & Talk Tokyo, 1997-10-16; 1 (Box 64)
  - Headlands documentation & Myrtle & Deathnet, 1996-07; 1 (Box 64)
  - At Home with Barbara Hammer, 1999-12-30; 1 (Box 64)
  - Lesbian Avengers at Alice Austin's House also ARTS section Barbara Hammer, 1994-07-31; 1 (Box 64)
  - Barbara Hammer Iowa City, 1993-05-07; 1 (Box 64)
  - Misc. Germany Footage, 1991-09-04; 1 (Box 64)
  - Cancer news archival footage, undated; 1 (Box 65)
  - My workshop: C3TV - CRTV7 Cape Cod, undated; 1 (Box 65)
  - Yamagata Film Fest - Florrie / Me, undated; 1 (Box 65)
  - Barbara Hammer - Women of Vision, 1997-03-27; 1 (Box 65)
  - Women of Vision by Alexandra Juhasz, undated; 2 (Box 65)
  - Claude Cahun NSYLA, undated; 1 (Box 66)
  - Sisters Resisters Lovers Others Tape 2 Camera 2, undated; 1 (Box 66)
  - Generations short for possible audio, undated; 1 (Box 66)
  - Unidentified audio recordings by Chris Blue, circa 2016; 1 (Box 66)
  - Unidentified footage--1 shot to Beta for Barbara Hammer, 2003; 1 (Box 66)
  - French Resistance: Henri Matisse GC clip, undated; 1 (Box 66)
  - Julia Stoschek Collection, 2017; 1 (Box 66)
  - Moments in Time vol. 4, 1993; 1 (Box 66)
  - "La Freak" by Demies-Soeurs, undated; 1 (Box 66)
  - Crazy in Joy Woods at 29 Years, 2013; 1 (Box 66)
- Electronica media, 1997-2014; Series V; 0.83; (2 boxes)
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Contains materials related to Barbara Hammer's work as a filmmaker and artist including computer files, footage, images, project notes, writings, research materials.
  - LOVER OTHER - BERLIN FLYER, undated; 1 (Box 67)
  - LO Time code transcript final, undated; 1 (Box 67)
  - Lover Other- Dialogue - Press Packet, undated; 1 (Box 67)
  - JHT - all original scans + one copy of 1, 2003-11-12; 2 (Box 67)
  - Ms.Ryan, the Ama Diver, undated; 2 (Box 67)
  - Hae Ney photographs, undated; 1 (Box 67)
  - Tenju-do stills, undated; 1 (Box 67)
  - Masculinity/Femininity - Blu-ray, 2014; 1 (Box 67)
  - Masculinity/Femininity DVD, 2014; 1 (Box 67)
  - Shirley Clarke plaque unveiling ceremony, 2006; 1 (Box 67)
  - Jeju project files, music, and footage, 2007; 1; 9 (Box 67)
  - Diving Woman project files, 2007; 3 (Box 67)
  - Photos, project files, and documentation, circa 2002-2005; 6 (Box 68)
  - Photos, project files, and documentation, circa 2001-2007; 6 (Box 68)
  - An Activist Life--student oral history project, 2008-11-30; 2 (Box 68)
  - Photos, project files, and documentation, circa 2005-2007; 8; 1 (Box 68)
  - Stringed Moments--Daniel Bernard Roumain, 2001; 1 (Box 68)
  - Ceremonial Reglementaire et Traditions Militaires, 1997; 1 (Box 68)
- Costumes, clothing, and accessories, 1979-2015; Series VI; 5.42; (5 boxes)
  Contains materials related to Barbara Hammer's work as a filmmaker and artist including clothing, costumes, jewelry, and wigs.
  - T-shirts, circa 1979-2000 (Box 69)
    Includes t-shirts from the Gay and Lesbian Film Festival, Women Make Waves Film/Video Festival, and the Lolita Raclin Rogers Memorial Conference on Feminist Film Criticism.
  - Costumes, undated (Box 70)
  - Costumes, undated (Box 71)
  - Costume and accessories, circa 2015 (Box 72)
    Contains scripts, costumes, and accessories related to the "Canceled From Memory" experimental lecture given at RISD and a performance called 'ReINcarnation: Barbara Hammer as Claude Cahun"
  - Costume accessories and optical lenses, undated (Box 73)
    Includes a hat, wigs, jewelry, and other costume accessories used by Hammer. Also contains a small collection of bifocal and other lenses obtained from Hammer's optometrist circa 1967, used in the production of Hammer's film "Schizy."